I’m Professor Dave, and I wanna teach you
how to speak Italian.
Ciao, bello.
So you’d like to learn Italian.
Or at least you’re a little curious.
It’s easy to see why you would be; there
are many reasons one would want to speak this
beautiful language.
Perhaps you want to impress your date by reading
confidently from an Italian Restaurant menu.
Maybe you want to see a Puccini opera and
know what the heck is going on.
There are authors whose works you may want
to enjoy in the original language, like Dante
Alighieri.
You might want to watch films by the great
Italian directors, Fellini and Sorrentino,
without having to read poorly translated subtitles.
Maybe you need Italian for business.
Italy’s major brands are recognized all
over the world, and many of them need employees
that speak the language.
Italy is also a leader in wine production.
So a little Italian will definitely up your
sophistication.
If none of these lofty pursuits fit the bill,
you’re either looking for a few phrases
to use on your upcoming Italy trip, or you’re
taking Italian in school and you need a little help.
No matter what the reason, I’m here for
you.
These tutorials will include fun vocabulary
that’s broken down by category, as well
as easy-to-understand explanations for all
the tricky grammar you will encounter.
You can watch them all, or just the ones you
need.
A hidden bonus that comes with learning Italian
is that since it’s a Romance language, meaning
it was derived from Latin, learning Italian
will make it much easier to learn any other
Romance language, like Spanish, French, Portuguese,
or Romanian, all while challenging your brain
with something new.
And you’ll quickly be rewarded for your
efforts, because Italian is one of the easier
languages to learn.
There are no disappearing consonants like
in French, and if you speak English, you don’t
have to learn a new alphabet like with Chinese
or Arabic.
All the letters and sounds are ones you already
know, so Italian phonetics are easy to pick up.
There are more subtle benefits to learning
another language as well.
Becoming familiar with how another culture
thinks and communicates will broaden your
worldview, and expose you to emotions and
modes of thought that you never would have
come across otherwise, and Italians certainly
know how to express themselves.
Their language has a gorgeous musicality that
elevates even the most mundane phrase.
Like this one: Oggi andiamo al mare.
See?
You’re learning already!
So grab a Campari and soda, sit back, and
let’s learn some Italian.